DAVID WHITE-GOODE

goodescientist@gmail.com Brooklyn, New York (646) 709-3405 <u>linkedin.com/in/davidwhitegoode/</u> github.com/forextroll

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I have roughly two years in tech with an IT background but have always been interested in working with software and making engaging applications. With this goal I recently pursued a coding bootcamp with General Assembly, graduating from its Software Engineering Immersive program. I am eager to apply my experience in a software developer role.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Fellow | New York, NY

Feb 2022 - May 2022

General Assembly

- Participated in 12 weeks of rigorous project-based learning becoming competent in working with the MERN stack, including Python, and PostgreSQL.
- Built out several solo and group projects deployed with Heroku, Netlify, and MongoDB Cloud.

Day-Trader | Alhambra, CA

Apr 2020 - Jul 2021

Self-Employed

- Managed trades based on chart patterns, news, and earnings.
- Taught myself technical analysis and options trading strategies for maximizing upside and minimizing risk.
- Kept track of trades in Excel.

Data Analyst | Rosemead, CA

Jun 2019 – Mar 2020

Southern California Edison

- Monitored automated ETL (extraction, transformation and loading) jobs for failures or errors, resolving them myself or escalating as necessary through our ticketing system.
- Ran SQL code to retrieve and load data to produce reports and logs.

EDUCATION

General Assembly | New York, NY

Feb 2022 - May 2022

Certificate Software Engineering Immersive

CUNY New York City College of Technology | Brooklyn, NY

Jan 2016 - Dec 2018

Bachelor of Science in Computer Systems, magna cum laude

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages: Javascript/HTML/CSS, SQL/PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Frameworks and Libraries: Node.js, React, Mongoose
- Tools: Git/github, Heroku, Netlify, MongoDB Cloud

PROJECTS

Hater App (https://haterip.netlifv.app/) A social media site modeled playfully as the "evil twin" of Twitter.

- Developed in React, Django, Python, and PostgreSQL and hosted using Netlify.
- Implemented user stories defined by a product owner and fulfilled criteria for a minimal viable product criteria.

The Inner Bod (theinnerbod.netlify.app/) A website built in react that helps the user make healthy choices.

- Worked within a scrum team to develop solutions to users' health inquiries.
- Built a REST API using Express and Mongoose.
- Incorporated regular standups, sprints, and task estimation.